Here's how to really cash in on this
year. Number one, get serious. Life is serious.
We call it life or death. Somebody asked me one
time if I had a good description of life. I said,
yes, I think I've got a good one. Life
is the struggle to keep death at a respectable distance.
Right? Death seems to want to move in
prematurely, prematurely. If you want to live a good,
long, flourishing life, you got to push back. You
can't just give in. You got to push back.
That's what these products are for, to help
you push back. And we're dealing with some serious
matters here. So we can't just, you know, tell
the latest 10 jokes and just go home. We're not
here to entertain. We're here to instruct. We're here
to grow. We're here to learn. We're here to
get the best we possibly can. Serious. Life
is serious. The future is serious. One ancient
novelist said, these are the best of
times and these are the worst of times.
And for some of those who came
across this platform, it's extravaganza, million dollar
year incomes. For them, it's the best of times.
But I want you to know that while they're getting
the diamonds and the millions, there are a
lot of people around the world. For them,
it is the worst of times. The best of
times and the worst of times. That's called serious matter.
How come such a difference from those who
can reach such incredible heights and those who
haven't yet found the answers for their life and
their life? I don't know. I don't know. I don't
know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't
know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't long
to her. I don't know. They've always wanted
to change it. Not that I agree with their
own gray hat now that all the PI is gonna
change it and which have been pleasant to me in their
youth. I am thinking heat. I remember it that
much an age and where it was not. And so
when I met her I just said, God
she will get it again in seven days.
Now, I haven't had the need for just anything
except for this kind of public. I don't think
this is what I would expect before I came
here to be my mother. But just the note of
that, he says, You cannot prevent the universe
from siendo a laughable treasure in any way.
But when you see with your own eye that
the Galaxy and ją nostrils around sun and it
lose. It's serious whether you succeed or fail.
It's serious whether you've got a good future
carved out for yourself or you do not have.
These are serious matters. Matters of the heart are
serious. Matters of income are serious. Matters
of supporting your family, serious. That's why
Herbalife. It's about the most serious company I've
ever been around in my 33 years of executive
lifetime. I've never met anybody more serious. We
used to have in sharing the product story, right?
Had the button lose weight now, ask me how.
And somebody says, how? Our first words were what?
Are you serious? Why? We've got a serious matter
here to discuss. We haven't come with the latest
10 stories. We've come with a serious matter. And
I want you to take on that serious tone.
You've got some serious products that answer
a serious need out there in the marketplace.
And I'm asking you to take it serious. Take your
own future serious. What you can do for your family
is to take it serious. Take it serious.
Take it serious. Take it serious. Take it serious.
Take it serious. This is serious business. So that's
the first thing I want to bring to you.
To have the best year ever this year.
Help contribute to the 400 million. Take your piece
of the 400 million. I don't know how much
of that you want. It's really not that much.
For 400 of us, it's only a million dollars.
For 800 of us, it's only a half a million
dollars. Half a million dollars, that's almost getting to be ridiculous.
For a lot of people in this room, half a million dollars.
And I don't know what piece of that 400 million you want,
but I'm asking you to seriously take
on a piece of that 400 million.
So that you can say, I made my
best and finest contribution to see that goal reached.
Not just for the figure, for the
figure, but for all that the figure represents.
For the healing it represents. For the
restoration of broken lives that it represents.
And people that are discouraged about their life
and their chances, now encouraged on a new road.
For all that that represents, 400 million. Take your share
of the 400 million and let's get the job done.
Take a piece of this and let's go for it.
And then when we finish that one, we'll set another one.
And when we finish that one, we'll set another one.
And when they write the history books, they will say,
those Herbal Life distributors took
on the responsibility, got out there,
touched people's lives, and nobody's made a
better contribution to the health of the country
than the Herbal Life distributors.
Let that be our reputation.
I've got a new seriousness going for me. You know,
I could have quit and played a long time ago.
When Mark and Larry called me, right? Hey, I'm semi-retired.
I'm looking for the next example.
That's good, that's good.
But here, my view is, I— Did your
aunt ever do that?
No.
Learn from your own experiences.
One way to learn to do
it right is do it wrong.
That's one way to learn to do it right.
Do it wrong.
Now the key is don't let it take too long.
If you've done it wrong for
a year, we suggest that's long enough.
You don't need another year just to prove a point.
No, one year is enough.
Learn from your own experience, right?
So the call didn't go well, all the stuff.
Guess what they did when they finished that call?
They made another call.
What else could we do to make it better?
How could we possibly improve?
This is called the possibility
for life change starts with education.
Don't be lazy in learning.
Don't be lazy in picking up the ideas.
Don't be lazy in learning from your own experience.
That's why you've heard from some people
that have shared their testimonial here and given
you some of their ideas.
Some of their ways and means of taking
this product to the marketplace, making it work
for you.
We've devoted most of our time
for that and well, we should.
Learning is the beginning of wealth.
Learning is the beginning of life change.
Some people want to start with
motivation, but you don't start with motivation.
You can tell we don't spend
that much time on motivation, right?
Some companies, right, by now they'd be standing
on the chairs, waving the flag, singing the
old gray mare or some silly thing.
That's not Herbalife.
We've got a serious task to do and we're here.
Enough motivation, certainly.
But here's the best motivation we've got going.
The proof of our success.
When we bring our success stories
to this platform, that's enough motivation.
When we bring our dedication and let it show,
we let the work of our hands show, that's
the motivation we want, right?
Not just excitement.
Just excitement alone won't do it.
Somebody says, just motivate this guy, he'll be all right.
The answer is no, probably not.
If a guy's an idiot, you motivate him.
Now you've got a motivated idiot.
No.
So education, get smart, don't miss the training class.
You say, well, I've already
been to one of those classes.
I've already heard it.
I've got a good phrase for you to take home.
That's no sign you got it.
Just because you've listened to those millionaire tapes
one time is no sign you've got it.
I'm asking you to listen to
them over and over and over.
I'm asking you to dedicate yourself to
a new level of learning in 1992.
When I travel with Mark
Hughes, he's got his book open.
He's got a book open.
He's reading, he's studying lives of
successful people, lives of despicable people.
Study, learn, grow, change, develop.
Never let it be said.
You didn't learn.
You gotta learn.
Right?
If you want to solve your problems, you gotta learn.
If you want to take advantage
of an opportunity, you gotta learn.
We can't come here and just give you the
marketing plan, give you the product, send you home.
We gotta stay for a while.
Learn, stay for a while.
Right?
Put on those cassettes and stay for a while.
We asked you to come here for a
couple of days and stay for a while.
Do some learning.
Take it back home.
So number two, to have your best year
ever, a good piece of that 400 million.
Make your dreams come true.
Number one is get serious.
Number two, get smart.
Develop your own personal philosophy here.
Philosophy, major determining factor in
how your life works out.
Each person's philosophy is like the set of the sail.
The same wind blows on us all.
The difference in where we arrive at the end of
the week, at the end of the month, at the
end of the year is not the wind that blows.
And the wind is blowing around the world.
The world is in solution.
Things are changing.
The walls have come down.
All kinds of things that are happening.
In Russia tonight, today the winds are blowing.
But what's going to make the major difference?
Each person's personal philosophy that sets
a better sail, sets a better sail.
So don't ask for a more favorable wind.
That's like wishing something that's not going to occur.
Don't ask for better seed and soil.
All you got's what's available.
Don't curse what you got.
On this planet, all we got.
We got the wind.
the seed that's here, the soil that's here, the miracle of
life that's here, the opportunity that's here, the seasons that are here.
That's all we got.
Wherever you've come from in your country,
the economy you got, that's all you got.
In America, our economy, that's all we got.
The government, that's all we got.
The marketplace, that's all we got.
Whatever you do, don't criticize all you got.
The key is to set a better sale and
turn what you've got into the miracle of your future.
Don't wish it was easier.
Wish you were better.
Don't wish for less problems.
Wish for more skills.
And that's the reason for coming here,
spending a couple of days of intense effort,
taking notes, rolling up your sleeves, going to work.
Commit yourself to learning so that you
can get smarter for the days ahead.
Develop your philosophy.
Herbalife's philosophy has carried it now
these 12 years to extraordinary heights.
Those who do the work get the pay.
A philosophy that commits itself to having
the finest no matter what it costs.
That kind of philosophy.
I'm asking you to develop.
Develop your own personal philosophy.
Get your business philosophy going.
Get your financial plan going.
Don't violate the conclusions of your own
philosophy by not executing and taking action.
But that's number two.
Get smart.
Here's number three.
Get going.
As smart as you might become after these two
days, as many ideas as you take away from here,
they're truly, as Larry mentioned, like
seeds to be planted in the soil.
They're really nice ornate, but
it's really lighter than you realize.
You've got to get going.
You've got to take action.
The disciplines is the miracle process.
And here's how to get the miracle of
your future going as far as disciplines are concerned.
Number one, do what you can.
You might go home and set a whole new
pace for yourself and we call it cleaning up neglect.
Should walk around the block, could walk
around the block for your good health.
Don't walk around the block.
See you're on the wrong track.
Should walk around the block to achieve your goals.
Should walk around the block.
Don't walk around the block.
Should read, could read, don't read, on the wrong track.
Should call, could call, don't call, on the wrong track.
Could change, should change, don't
change, you're on the wrong track.
Letters you haven't written, conversations
you haven't had with your family,
somebody you should sit down with when
you get back home, get that job done.
Don't let neglect destroy your days,
destroy your life, and destroy your future.
Go back and do what you can.
And if you'll do what you can, then
life will give you some extraordinary things to do.
We all pity the man, right?
Wants to stride out of his
house, go straighten out the corporation,
has not yet straightened out his garage.
You got to take care of the small
disciplines before life will give you a chance
to handle the more complicated disciplines.
How do you think Mark Hughes got here?
Scattered now throughout 14, 15
countries, another 14, 15 coming up.
I mean, how do you do this?
You start first with the smallest
of disciplines and do not neglect them
and do not disregard them as being trifling.
Everything matters.
Everything's important.
Good phrase to take home.
All disciplines affect each other.
In fact, here's a good philosophical phrase.
If you hadn't thought of it before, here it is.
Everything affects everything else.
It's so easy to be casual
and say, well, this doesn't matter.
This doesn't matter.
I'm telling you everything.
It matters.
Of course, some things matter more than others,
but there isn't anything that doesn't matter.
Then here's the positive side.
Every new discipline affects all your other disciplines.
If you'll get some new things going,
make some calls you've never made before,
step up your activity level, step up your labor level,
develop the skills from these two days of training here,
and you'll go home and
work some miracles on your days
and your life and your
future and your income, your business,
and a bigger portion of that
$400 million will certainly be yours.
Go for the disciplines, the smallest of disciplines,
the least of disciplines,
like keeping your accounts in order,
the smallest of disciplines.
Did you ever hear this expression?
I don't know where it all goes.
Did you ever hear that?
Wow.
Oh, we'd love to have you run Herbalife.
You don't know where it all goes.
How long do you think we'd last here in Herbalife,
if that was your philosophy sitting
at the top like Mark Hughes?
Let me give you the story on Mark Hughes.
Mark knows where everything goes.
And he started back when he only had pennies.
He started back when he only had dollars.
He started back when he didn't have much.
But here's the key, one
of the greatest extraordinary phrases
that's ever been written from antiquity says,
if you'll be faithful,
if you'll be disciplined when the amounts are small,
we'll make you a ruler,
give you a position of
authority when the amounts are many.
Somebody says I've only got two or three distributors,
I don't know where they are.
Come on.
If you've only got two or three,
you can know when they get up,
you can know when they go to bed.
You can know all the details.
Take care of your disciplines when the amounts are small.
And then life will see to it that
you get some extraordinary numbers to work with,
like you saw the stories displayed here.
Do not disregard the smallest of disciplines.
Let us not neglect.
Do not neglect the smallest of
disciplines and build on that foundation,
and you can have everything you could possibly want.
Okay?
Get going.
Thank you.
Here's number four.
Get better.
There isn't any of us that can't get better,
so turn on this whole idea
of personal development and personal growth.
That was what my teacher shared
with me that changed my life,
starting a few steps from here at that convention.
I'm telling you, for things to
get better, you've got to get better.
Don't ask for it to change out there.
Ask for you to change here.
Don't ask for a more favorable wind.
We call that naive.
Don't ask for better seed, better soil.
This is the only planet you got.
Just ask that you can
get wiser and stronger and better,
be able to take care of your own responsibilities.
Get better.
Learn how to handle the seasons better.
Let's go through them.
Some stuff I did on satellite many, many years ago.
Let me just review those notes
for you on this getting better part.
Learn how to handle the seasons of life.
Number one, learn how to handle the winters.
We're all going to go through some winters.
Herbalife's been through a few.
Just the winters of the
calendar in the last 12 years.
How many winters?
About 12.
But it's not just the winters of the calendar.
It's not just the winters of the seasons.
There's all kinds of winters.
The winter when you can't figure it out.
The winter when it all goes wrong.
The winter when you have all kinds of heckles.
All kinds of hecklers on a telephone call.
Right?
The winter when you get that first half dozen refunds.
The winters of your life.
Social winters.
Political winters that we're going through around the world.
Economic winters that a lot
of people are experiencing these days.
Personal winters when your heart
is smashed in a thousand pieces
and the nights are unusually long.
It is simply called winter time.
But here's what you've got to do.
And your own personal development.
Your own personal growth.
And that is just get better at handling the winters.
You can't change the winter.
You can't change the seasons.
But you can change yourself.
You say, well, what can I do
about the upcoming winters of my life?
The challenges that I know I'm going to face.
Here's what you can do.
You can get wiser and stronger and better.
Just make a list of that trio of words.
Wiser, stronger and better.
Go home smarter than you came.
Go home with more ideas than you came with.
Next, get stronger.
You can develop the muscle.
You can develop the courage muscle.
You can develop the inspiration muscle.
You can develop the dedication muscle.
You can get stronger.
There isn't anybody here that can't get stronger.
Next time we see you may not even recognize you.
How strong you're going to be able
to become in language and style and personality.
The ability to cope.
The ability to handle.
With anything that happens.
No matter what happens.
And the third one is get better.
We can all get better.
I've gotten better.
First talk I gave.
I stood up.
My mind sat back down.
I love to wait for the translation to finish.
See if I can get some more reaction here.
But here's the secret to my success.
I stood up and did it again.
I stood up and I did it again.
And I did it again.
All those many years ago.
I did it when I was scared and
I did it when I didn't want to.
And I did it when I was ill.
And I did it when it didn't work.
Well, I didn't did it when they didn't appreciate it.
And I didn't a lot of times when
I didn't know much what I was doing.
I just did it anyway.
And now all these years later,
I'm asked to walk on this stage.
With the greatest introduction I've ever had.
Greatest response and welcome I've ever had.
The greatest opportunity I've ever had to touch this many
lives with a mixture of words and heart and soul.
I got better.
I got better day by day and
week by week and month by month.
And I'm asking you to do the same thing until
you can develop a long arm and a long reach.
Until you can develop influence that won't quit.
Touch people next year you couldn't touch this year.
Touch people now you couldn't touch before.
Conduct a meeting now you couldn't conduct before.
Heart and soul now mixed in there that wasn't there.
Missing before.
I'm asking all of you to
get better in spite of the winters.
In spite of the downturn.
The money downturn.
The social downturn.
The personal downturn.
Whatever it is.
Just get stronger.
Get better.
We've all got those personal winters.
We know what those are like.
Barbra Streisand sings, it used to
be so natural to talk about forever.
But,
used to be these don't count anymore.
They just lay on the
floor till we sweep them away.
You don't sing me love songs.
You don't say you need me.
And you don't bring me flowers anymore.
A winter song.
But hey, we're acquainted with all those
personal winters and all the rest of it.
The key is not to wish for a better winter.
The key is to wish for
more strength, more wisdom, more courage.
Get better.
Get wiser.
Get stronger.
Here's number two.
Learn to take advantage of the spring.
Spring means opportunity.
And we've got a fresh spring going here.
It's called a spring like no other.
A spring and opportunity like no other for you.
But here's the clue.
Spring is not a guarantee of a harvest
in the fall and the autumn harvest time.
Here's what you must learn to do.
Underline the two words if you're taking notes.
Take.
Advantage.
Take advantage of the spring.
Don't just be faked out by the
spring because the nice weather has come.
Looks like everything is going to be a lot better.
The winter's finally passed.
The spring is here.
I'm telling you that's not
going to do it for you.
Just because the spring is here is
not going to do it for you.
You got to seize it with your own two hands.
And take advantage.
Read the books.
Study the tapes.
Go back through your notes.
Get ready to cash in on the spring.
And now there's a sense of urgency here.
Here's why.
Spring doesn't last that long.
To be able to say I
just got back doesn't last that long.
It's called the springtime of opportunity.
Postpone a few things in the springtime.
Get the job done.
Set aside a few things in the springtime.
Where I was raised in Idaho farm country.
What if you asked a farmer
to go bowling in the spring?
What would he probably say?
He would say you're insane.
You can go bowling in the winter.
When you can't plant the crop.
You can't go bowling in the spring.
You've only got a certain piece of time.
And you got to get it
done in that certain window of opportunity.
And that's what we've got here.
A window of opportunity.
Let's take advantage of it.
It's called take advantage of the spring.
And there's also an urgency here.
How many springs have you got in a lifetime?
Not very many.
Let's take advantage of it.
Life is brief at the longest.
The Beatles wrote life is very short.
And for John Lennon it was extra short.
For Michael Landon it was extra short.
But it is short.
There's an urgency here.
Don't waste your springs.
Don't just let them pass, pass,
pass hoping the time will pass.
Take advantage.
Last year it was seize the bull.
It was seize the moment.
And I'm asking you now this
season to seize the spring opportunity.
You've got a new organization going.
Seize the spring.
You've got a new distributor going.
You've got a new life situation going.
Seize the spring.
Take advantage of it.
Don't let it pass without giving it the
best of your two hands and your attention.
Number three.
First, learn how to handle the winter.
Second, take advantage of the spring.
Number three.
In the summer.
Learn to nourish and protect.
We've got some major challenges now come summertime.
One is to nourish our values.
Take care of them. Feed them.
Don't let them go hungry.
Don't let them go wanting in nourishment and care.
Then here's something else we've
got to do in the summer.
Defend ourselves against the enemies.
Summertime is a unique time.
It's a time of opportunity.
It's also a time of challenge.
But what else is new?
It's what life is called.
The last six and a
half thousand years reads like this.
Opportunity mixed with difficulty.
Opportunity mixed with challenge.
We've got a chance to grow like never before.
But I'm telling you there's going to be
many enemies that's going to try to prevent us.
As soon as you plant the garden, the busy
bugs and the noxious weeds are out to take it.
And you've got to learn to take advantage of it.
And you've got to learn
not only to nourish your values.
You've got to learn to do battle with your enemies.
Whatever threatens you, I'm asking you to threaten it back.
Take care of your responsibility.
But don't take anything off anybody.
Somebody wants to destroy your chances for a good future
by their negative talk, negative thinking, putting it all down.
I'm telling you, walk away if you have to.
Walk away.
Whatever threatens you, threaten it back.
Whatever threatens your opportunity, threaten it back.
Now some of our enemies are on the outside.
But here's the most important thing to understand.
Some of our enemies are on the inside.
Let me give you a quick list.
Indifference.
You've got to do battle with your own indifference.
Boy, it's easy to coast.
Especially if you've accomplished
something, you know, extraordinary now.
Somebody says, I've got to relax.
Here's the key.
Not too long.
The weak will be the strong.
The weeds will take all your
plant if you rest too long.
Don't rest too long.
Indecision.
You've got to make those decisions.
The ones that don't turn out to be
good gives you experience to make better decisions.
Don't let much time go by without making some decisions.
The ones that you can make quickly, make them quickly.
The ones that take time, take your time.
But get those decisions made.
Don't let indecision be an enemy, rob you of the future,
empty your bank account, leave you with zero in the purse.
Don't let that happen.
The next one is doubt.
Sure, there's doubts on the outside.
People doubt that America's going to make it.
People doubt that Europe's going to make it.
People doubt that Russia's going to make it.
The Poland's going to make it.
The Czechoslovakia's going to make it.
They doubt the whole world is going to make it.
But I'm asking you not
to pick up all those doubts.
I'm asking you to have some faith.
Have some courage.
Believe.
Drive your doubts into a small corner.
Don't let them loose like a mad dog.
Drive you into a small corner.
Don't doubt the future.
Don't doubt the possibilities.
Don't doubt the extraordinary gifts that
your distributors bring to your organization.
Don't doubt that.
And here's the most important one of all.
Don't doubt yourself.
If I've got miracle working power
to change my life, so do you.
If I've got the ability to change, so do you.
If I've got the ability to read, so do you.
If I can discover, so can you.
If I can grow, you can grow.
If I can develop, you can develop.
If I can get an invitation like I got six
years ago, help take something around the world, so can you.
If I can stand on this platform,
Idaho farm boy raising obscurity, so can you.
If the millionaire team can do it, president's team can do
it, walk off with the diamonds, the trophies, so can you.
I'm asking you don't sell yourself short.
We haven't sold you short.
That's why Mark, Larry, and Dr. Katzen and
I, we've been doing this for a long time.
And I've decided to invest a big share of our
life these four days in being with all of you.
If we didn't think you were
worth it, we wouldn't have showed up.
We don't need to conduct another meeting.
We don't need to walk on another stage.
We don't need to get
up early like we get up.
Don't need it.
Except for the challenge and the opportunity
to invest in this many people's lives.
Who wouldn't get up early to have a chance
to work miracles and invest in this many people's lives
and help turn the world upside
down for better nutrition called herbal life.
Here's the next one, worry.
I'm asking you to drive worry into a small corner.
You gotta worry some.
All this negative stuff serves some purpose.
But the key is for you
to be the master, not the servant.
If it's 2 o'clock in the morning,
you're gonna be the master.
You're gonna be the servant.
If it's 2 o'clock in the morning and
your daughter's not home yet, best you worry.
In New York City, if you step off the curb
and one of those yellow taxis is coming, best you worry.
But here's what I'm asking you to do.
You be the master of worry.
Drive it into a small corner.
Don't let it loose.
And I'm asking you to go home
with some new faith and some new courage.
I'm asking you, don't worry.
Drive it into a small corner.
We've all got concerns.
And sometimes we all wonder.
And sometimes there's a little crack of doubt.
We worry a little.
But I'm telling you, drive it into a small corner.
Drive your worries into a small corner.
I promise you from this platform,
the dedication of the executives that
you've seen and the president's team members
and the people that have
walked off with 1 through 10,
I'm telling you, we're all dedicated to help
this Herbalife future that includes all of you
be the most spectacular thing that's happened in the 90s.
I promise you.
I promise you not to
worry because you're in good hands.
You're in good hands.
And now what I want
you to be able to say,
if you give Mark Hughes a telephone call
or if you have a chance
to talk to Mark Hughes in person,
whatever village you've come from, whatever street
you've come from, wherever you've come from,
I'd like for you to be
able to say sincerely and honestly,
with all the dedication you possibly can,
Mark Hughes, I want you to go to
bed at night and sleep like a baby.
Because where I came from, when I
go back and represent Herbalife in that community,
I want to reassure you, Mark Hughes,
Herbalife in that community is in good hands.
I want some of you from Germany,
get together, form a little coalition from Germany.
After you've gotten out there
and gotten your hands into it
and you've had a chance to work in
labor for a while, send Mark Hughes a message
and say, Mark Hughes, the distributors
that have now joined forces in Germany,
you can rest easy, Mark Hughes.
In Germany, Herbalife is in good hands.
And all of the rest of
the countries, make that your dedication.
Make it personally. Make it collectively as an organization.
This incredible opportunity has been dropped on
our lap, it's been given to us,
we're going to take it to the marketplace and we're
going to take it to the marketplace with good hands.
Steady hands, growing hands, intelligent hands that can
go touch people and get the job done.
I'm asking you to commit to that.
Herbalife is in good hands.
Couple of more enemies of the mind you
got to do battle with in the summer.
One is pessimism that tries to get
you only to see the negative side.
Of course, there's the negative side.
Like it or not, there's the negative side.
Herbalife is part negative, what else is new?
If the glass is half empty, it is half empty.
You say, well, I've been only
taught to see that it's half full.
Well, sure, it's half full.
But it's also half empty.
I mean, can't you handle that?
I mean, you know, that's not too difficult.
But here's what pessimism would
try to get you to do.
Believe that it's only half empty.
And when pessimism comes to your mind,
you've got to educate pessimism because pessimism is stupid.
Pessimism tries to get you to
believe that it's only half empty.
You got to say, pessimism, you've never been to school.
Too dumb and stupid to know.
Of course, it's half empty,
but it's not only half empty.
It's also half full.
I'm asking you to be in charge.
Be in charge of your own mind.
Be in charge of your own destiny.
Do battle with your enemy.
In the summertime,
in the summertime,
you've got to learn to love like a mother.
Hate like a father.
Give life like a mother.
Nourish.
Take life like a father.
Father says to whatever threatens his family,
take two or three more steps
toward this family and threaten them.
You'll cease to exist.
I'm father.
I kill.
Do battle with your enemies.
Now, it's also possible to love like a father
and hate like a mother.
I'm not saying that isn't possible.
Nothing more dangerous than an angry mother.
Thank you.
I saw an article in a magazine
a little bit ago up in Canada.
It showed a man with
some claw marks on his back,
had his shirt off, big teeth marks in his neck.
This man was out in
the woods, had his flash camera,
saw a mama bear with a little cub,
thought, oh, this is cute, took a flash picture.
Mama bear takes unkindly to this flash picture,
promptly chases the man, catches him, always kills him.
almost kills him before somebody rescued him. So
beware mama bear. Okay. Love like a father,
hate like a mother, give life like a mother, take
life like a father, or however you want to arrange
it. Just so you nourish your values,
nourish your family, nourish what's valuable for you,
nourish your organization, nourish
your distributors, nourish your customers,
take care of your responsibilities, feed, nourish. But
then I'm also asking you to do battle
with your enemies. Take sword to your
enemies. Whatever's going to destroy those values,
take sword to it. If it's worry, take sword to
it. If it's threat, threaten back. You got to be
like your bloodstream. Good illustration. Red
corpuscles to nourish like a mother.
White corpuscles to fight and kill like a father.
You got to do some
negative thinking and just think positive.
Thank God for white corpuscles that think negative all day.
White corpuscles say, just show
me some infection, I'll kill it.
Whatever threatens this body and its future gets threatened.
Whatever's not to kill it, it's not to kill it.
This body gets killed. I'm asking you, take
sword to your enemies, whether they're on the outside
or whether they're on the inside. Protect
your family, protect your future, protect your values.
Love, nourish, but also do battle with
whatever's out there to do battle with you.
Take some courage from some of those that
have been through the battle. They've given you their
stories on this stage. They've been through it.
They know what it's all about. Take some courage
from that. And in the summer, do battle and nourish.
Now, here's the last one
in the harvest time. Number four.
Take your harvest and all that
comes your way with full responsibility.
Don't complain.
That fourth season complaining, I'm telling
you, could ruin all of your chances.
Complaining sometimes starts as an infection. If you
don't take care of it, it becomes a disease.
Do battle with it. In the harvest time,
reap your harvest without complaint. It's your crop,
you sowed it. You either made the calls
or didn't make the calls. You wrote the letters,
you didn't write the letters. You were steady or you
weren't steady. You did it or you didn't do it.
You put together a good day or you
didn't put together a good day. Take responsibility when
the harvest time finally comes and say, hey, it's
my crop. Got to take responsibility for it. I do
not complain. And then here's
the next one. Do not apologize.
If you've done well,
we offer no apologies. When these winners that
walked across this stage here go back to their
communities. We offer no apology for making the kind
of money they make because of the lives they
touched and the people that they helped. No
telling what would have happened if these people
had not touched many people's lives who touched
many people's lives. When you go back to the
community, all of you that were winners here, I
ask you to go back with no apology because you've
done your job well and you've given good hands to
everybody.
You've touched you deserve all the money.
Next, under getting better, I just want to make
you make this list of four words, four words.
First, we talked about getting serious.
Second, get smart.
Third, get going.
Fourth is get better.
And here's four good words to take home.
One is absorb, develop the skill
and the ability to absorb everything.
Be like a sponge like you've been today.
This has been a good, serious group.
I appreciate that.
You've worked as hard as we
have up here on this platform.
You've rolled up your sleeve and you've gone to
work and you've taken notes and I appreciate that.
Absorb everything you can absorb the
sights and the sounds and the color.
Guess what?
You're gonna want to do?
Go back home and invest this experience into other people's
lives and you can't invest it if you haven't got it.
So I'm asking you to appreciate the color.
I'm asking you to appreciate the auditorium
asking you to appreciate what's going on here.
I'm asking you to appreciate each other.
Soak this all up.
Soak it all up.
It's called absorb, absorb, absorb.
Then when you get back home, you can give out, give out, give out
and you'll have an extraordinary effect on the people that you reach out and touch.
Here's the next one.
Develop the ability to respond.
That's what got me almost six years ago.
Mark and Larry made that call.
I responded.
It touched me.
The vision they gave me, the story they gave me, the pictures they painted, the numbers they gave me, what we could do together, the team we could build,
dominate the industry, walk head and shoulders above anything else that's out there, have an extraordinary adventure that's only been given to a few, a chance to walk the summit.
Got me.
Touched me.
Now I'm asking you, however, not only
to be touched with the summit numbers.
The 400 million.
I'm asking you to be touched
with the smallest of people's challenges.
Don't just be touched with the challenge.
I'm asking you to be touched with the problem.
Let people's problems get to you.
Let people's problems touch your
heart this year like never before.
Be touched.
Let life touch you.
Don't let it kill you, but let it touch you.
The problems that are out there, people struggling with
their economy, struggling with their health, struggling with their future.
I'm asking you to let that get around you.
Let it get around your heart.
Let it do something to you.
Don't go untouched.
Don't go unmoved.
When you walk out of here, open yourself up.
Don't build up the walls.
The same wall that keeps out
disappointment keeps out happiness and opportunity.
Take the walls down.
Let yourself be touched by what's going on out there.
Let sad things make you sad as
well as happy things make you happy.
Let your heart get touched and you'll have good
hands then to take this product to the marketplace.
Here's number three.
Develop the ability to reflect.
Long after this session is over, I'm asking
you to go back over it one more time.
I'm asking you at the end of
the day, go back over your day.
the week, go back over your week.
Make that week more valuable.
At the end of the
month, go back over your month.
At the end of a
conversation, go back over the conversation.
How did it go and what did you do?
Learn by reflecting.
I call it run the
tapes again of your own experiences.
And you say, why do that?
Here's why.
To develop the extraordinary ability to gather up
the past and invest it in the future.
What a next year you could have
if you pay more attention this year.
Soak it up, gather it up, and reflect
at certain times what's going on and what's happening.
And this year will take a
more powerful place in your experience.
And then when you get ready to deliver in
1993, people will not believe the words you've chosen.
They will not believe the heart
and soul that you've mixed with words.
They won't believe the power you've got.
A few simple things here under getting better.
Then here's the last one, and that's to share.
We've got this extraordinary opportunity now.
Let us not keep it.
Let us share it.
Let us reach out with a long
reach, a strong reach, an unprecedented reach.
Let us reach out and touch
people not just with our opportunity.
Let's touch people with our lives.
Let's touch people with our experiences.
Let's touch people with our heart and soul.
Let's don't just touch people with
a marketing plan and a distributor kit.
Let's touch people with their health, yes.
With an opportunity, yes.
But here's a commitment I'd like
to have you make to me.
Let's help people with their lives, not just their health.
Let's help people with their lives, not just their income.
Let it be said, if they were
around us once, they would have done it.
If they were around us one
week, one month, or a lifetime.
That when they got around us,
not only did we talk about money,
not only did we talk
about product, we talked about life.
We talked about getting better.
We talked about becoming all that you can become.
We talked about picking up a challenge.
We talked about not settling for
less than you can possibly be.
Let's do that.
Let's develop those abilities.
That's why we're here.
Now here's my last two parts
to make this your best year ever.
Get excited.
And excitement is not just, you know, excitement.
Excitement that runs deep is the
excitement that really lasts for a lifetime,
not surface excitement. There's been a lot
of noise here, but what I really appreciate
and feel is that this room is full of
more than noise. It's full of more than sound.
I'll tell you what's really going to serve
you well, and that's the excitement you feel
inside that isn't even probably expressed on
the outside, the excitement that runs deep,
the excitement that stirs commitment, the
excitement that stirs courage. Give me the
chance and I will get the job done.
That kind of excitement. Develop that kind of attitude.
Get excited about your own skills. Get excited
about your own abilities. You can put it into
words. If I can start with nothing and finally stand
on this platform, I can do it.
I can perform, deliver, best words I can choose.
Words are clumsy at best when you try to express
what's going on in your heart, your head,
but I've done my best. What I'm telling you,
if I can find the words, you can
find the words. And here's a key here. Communicate.
Don't leave it unsaid. If somebody's got
some congratulations coming, don't fail to congratulate
them. If a distributor has got a word of
praise coming, don't fail to give it. Don't fail
to say it. Don't fail to say it.
Find the best words you can. Struggle with
the best words you can. Borrow some words
if you have to. I borrow all kinds
of words. Winston Churchill one time said, truth is
incontrovertible. Malice may attack it and ignorance
may deride it, but in the end, there
it is. See, I love to borrow that. I
mean, you know, that's better said than I could
say it. See, that's well said. You could stay up
on the moon. You could stay up on the moon.
You could stay up all night and not think
of that. I mean, that's well said. I'm asking
you to borrow the words that have come
from this platform. Borrow the words that have
come from the top 10. Borrow the words
that have come from the distributors who have shared
so eloquently with you. Borrow their words.
Borrow their notes. But then I'm asking you
to start choosing the best words you can. We
want you to get good at these skills of
communicating, skills of touching people's lives
with words, touching their heart with
words, helping them to see something they've never
been able to see. And that's what I'm
doing. I'm helping them to see something they've
never been able to see. And that's what I'm
asking you to start choosing the best words
you can with words, touching their heart with
words, touching their heart with words, touching
their heart with words, touching their heart
with words. You've seen a lot of the
words you've ever heard in or that you've ever
seen before by your words. Choose the best
words you can. Don't fail with an opportunity
to challenge yourself to choose good words.
Search for the words. Struggle for the words.
But don't let somebody within the scope
of your influence go without your words. Words
work miracles. Words can help people to
see something they've never seen before. There's
a lot of people you haven't got to
yet. They can't see how they can possibly correct
everything they're saying. Who knows? Thanks for listening
and I'll talk to you in a minute.
Take care.
be healthy. And if you'll come along with your
good words, you can turn on all the lights for
them. They can't see how they can possibly
be successful. And if you'll come along with your
testimonial, that's why Herbalife is built
on testimonials. Words that work, miracles,
help people to see. And when you come along
and tell your story, people are going to say,
before you got here, I was blind. And now that
you've talked to me, I can see. I can see the
possibilities. I can see the opportunity. I can see that
if I take a hold of this thing, I can
change my life. I can see it. I can see it.
I can see it. I'm asking you, don't miss the chance to
work miracles with your words. Get excited
about your possibility to work miracles with words.
And now here's my last word to you, and I'm
finished for this day. But let me give you this
last one. To make this your best year ever,
get away. Get away. Balance your life. Take care of
your family. Take care of your family. Take
care of your family. Take care of your family.
Take care of your responsibilities. Take care
of your spirituality. Take care of good
friendships. We've got to have some friends.
That's why I'm here. I made these extraordinary
friendships way back when. They've lasted all these
years. Now got me an invitation to participate
in something so extraordinary. This came about from
a friendship. Now I had the skills. Somebody
says, well, you know, they offered you millions
and a chance here just because you were friends.
No, you don't just offer your friends.
Millions and millions. No, they got to have some
skills. So I did bring skills, but I'm telling you,
my chance to bring my gifts and my skills
to you today was because I nourished these friendships
over all these years. So make
sure you balance your life, family, friendship.
Friends are those people who know
all about you and still like you.
Okay. You got to have some friends. You got
to have some friends. You got to have some friends.
You got to have some of those.
Take care of your spirituality. Balance your life.
We talk about nutrition. We talk about exercise.
We talk about money. We talk about future. And then
all the rest of it, don't leave it anything out.
Sundays Are